# MIKIO SAKAI

## FULL-STACK DEVELOPER



P +1 3165369224 E smileboth0805@gmail.com



Minato-ku, Tokyo, 105-0001



linkedin.com/in/mikio-sakai-986634227

## **OBJECTIVE**

I have 8 years of experience in web development and started it at the age of 22.

I love solving technical challenges and always try to keep myself up-to-date with technologies.

The things that I am focusing on in web development are understanding the business ideas clearly, writing clean/best-practice code, and making it easily understandable.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Nov 2021 - June 2022

Full-stack Developer, Simevo S.R.L

- Refactored Vue/Node code—reducing bugs, making it reusable, and altering it to provide new data utilized by the new data-visualization interfaces
- Used Amazon Lambda to increase the performance and secure the API endpoints
- Implemented multiplayer real-time features using Nuxt.js and WebSockets
- Used Amazon RDS for SQL databases and use it as the primary database
- Built daily GoogleSheet report using google-spreadsheet and node-cron library
- Wrote unit and end-to-end tests using Jest and Chai to ensure that the APIs are working as expected.
- Used Github and Gitlab CI/CD actions to implement CI and CD

## May 2017 - Oct 2021

Full-Stack Developer, Rain Interactive KK

- Optimized several large mongo queries where the execution time went down from 10 seconds to 1-2 seconds (sometimes sub-second).
- Implemented full-text search of articles using elasticsearch.
- Migrated MongoDB to Postgres on Node.js back-end
- Used Amazon S3 to store large files and MongoDB to store documents of Users, Accounts, Merchants, Transactions, etc.
- Developed cron-jobs for performing periodic features on the back-end side without any front-end requests
- Implemented live reloading of new product content and messages using socket.io.
- Built transactions and repayments report as excel and built a function of converting Docx files to pdf files

#### AREA OF EXPERTISE

- **BACK-END DEVELOPMENT**
- FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT
- **DEVOPS**

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- **VUE**
- **REACT**
- **NODE**
- DJANGO
- CI/CD
- **AWS**
- **GCP**
- **KUBERNETES**
- **DOCKER**

#### SOFT SKILLS

- **TESTING AND DEBUGGING**
- PROBLEM-SOLVING
- **EXCELLENT** COMMUNICATION
- **TEAMWORK**
- **MENTORING**
- **SELF-LEARNING**
- TIME MANAGEMENT

 Used mongo GridFSBucket/Google Cloud Storage to store large files like videos, audios, and images

#### Oct 2015 - Apr 2017

## Full-Stack Developer, Zo Digital Japan

- Built a responsive website front end using React/Redux
- Created several React components with D3 charts that support interactive visualizations of financial data projections and analysis
- Developed unit tests and integration tests using Jest and Chai
- Implemented client-side data transformations to map, filter, reduce, etc. large datasets for display in interactive SVG charts
- Wrote advanced jQuery DataTables plugins and UX handling
- Created a front-end application using React, which communicates with back-end API using JWT
- Displayed PDFs in React app as easily as if they were images
- Supported and refined a web service for storing data from social networks.

#### Apr 2014 - Sep 2015

#### Front-end Developer, Yumyapps

- Used react-webcam module to add camera features to React front-end
- Created reusable React components for the date picker, dropdown, buttons, and input styles according to the provided designs.
- Improved the UI and UX across the entire application with an overhaul of the existing CSS code.
- Contributed as part of the team that developed a new web-shop app for a large retailer.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Apr 2013 - Mar 2017

Tokyo University of Science, Bachelor of Science

## **SKILLS**

#### LANGUAGES

HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Python, Typescript, JavaScript, ES6

### FRAMEWORKS

Vue, Django, Express.js, Restify.js, Bootstrap

#### PARADIGMS

Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery, Scrum, Agile Software Development, Continuous Deployment

#### PLATFORMS

Distributed programming, Unit testing, Integration testing, Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Service

#### LIBRARIES/APIS

REST APIs, Vuex, Vuetify, React, jQuery, Google Maps, OpenCV, Sockets, Redux-Saga, React-Redux, Google API

## • TOOLS

Git, Terminal, Visual Studio Code, BitBucket, Gitlab, Jira, Sublime Text, Photoshop, Adobe XD, Mongo Compass, SQLyog

## • STORAGE

JSON, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Google Cloud Storage, AWS S3, Firestore